<idea-plugin>
    <id>io.github.hassandomedenea.alias-source-navigator</id>
    <name>Alias Source Navigator</name>
    <vendor email="hassan.domedenea@gmail.com" url="https://github.com/HassanDomeDenea">Hassan Dome Denea</vendor>

    <description><![CDATA[
        <p>
            Connects generated TypeScript auto-import aliases to their original source exports for
            both navigation and usage search.
        </p>
        <p>
            Designed for Vue and Vite projects using tools such as unplugin-auto-import and
            unplugin-vue-components. Instead of stopping in auto-imports.d.ts, imports.d.ts, or
            components.d.ts, navigation continues to the referenced composable, store, or component.
            Find Usages on a source export also includes references resolved through those generated
            declarations.
        </p>
        <p>
            Also supports Laravel Wayfinder: navigating a generated controller method such as
            <code>PatientController.autocomplete()</code> offers both the PHP controller method and
            the Wayfinder named TypeScript export.
        </p>
        <ul>
            <li>Supports named exports and default component exports.</li>
            <li>Handles relative typeof import(...) declaration aliases.</li>
            <li>Connects TypeScript and Vue auto-import usages back to source exports.</li>
            <li>Jumps from Wayfinder route methods to PHP controller methods.</li>
            <li>Leaves normal IDE navigation unchanged for non-alias symbols.</li>
        </ul>
    ]]></description>

    <change-notes><![CDATA[
        <p><b>0.3.1</b></p>
        <ul>
            <li>Fixes Wayfinder PHP navigation so Goto Declaration shows both the PHP method and the named TypeScript export.</li>
        </ul>
        <p><b>0.3.0</b></p>
        <ul>
            <li>Adds Laravel Wayfinder navigation from generated route methods to PHP controller methods.</li>
            <li>Offers dual targets for Wayfinder methods: PHP definition first, then the named TypeScript export.</li>
        </ul>
        <p><b>0.2.1</b></p>
        <ul>
            <li>Fixes read-access exceptions when Find Usages runs on a background thread.</li>
        </ul>
        <p><b>0.2.0</b></p>
        <ul>
            <li>Adds reverse usage discovery from source exports through generated auto-import declarations.</li>
            <li>Supports auto-imported usages in TypeScript and Vue consumers.</li>
        </ul>
        <p><b>0.1.0</b></p>
        <ul>
            <li>Initial release.</li>
            <li>Redirects generated auto-import declarations to their original source exports.</li>
        </ul>
    ]]></change-notes>

    <idea-version since-build="261"/>

    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>
    <depends>JavaScript</depends>
    <depends>com.jetbrains.php</depends>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <gotoDeclarationHandler
            implementation="io.github.hassandomedenea.aliassourcenavigator.WayfinderGotoDeclarationHandler"
            order="first"/>
        <gotoDeclarationHandler
            implementation="io.github.hassandomedenea.aliassourcenavigator.GeneratedAliasGotoDeclarationHandler"
            order="first"/>
        <referencesSearch
            implementation="io.github.hassandomedenea.aliassourcenavigator.GeneratedAliasReferencesSearcher"/>
    </extensions>
</idea-plugin>
